<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>communication on Nathaniel Schutta</title>
    <link>/tags/communication/</link>
    <description>Recent content in communication on Nathaniel Schutta</description>
    <generator>Source Themes academia (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2023 Nathaniel Schutta</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 15:23:49 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="/tags/communication/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Developer To Architect</title>
      <link>/abstracts/devtoarch/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 15:23:49 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/abstracts/devtoarch/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;full-abstract&#34;&gt;Full Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Becoming a software architect is a longed-for career upgrade for many software developers. While the job title suggests a work day focused on technical decision-making, the reality is quite different. In this workshop, software architect Nathaniel Schutta constructs a real world job description in which communication trumps coding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Discover the skill sets needed to juggle multiple priorities, meetings, and time demandsLearn why your best team leadership tool is not a hammer, but a shared cup of coffeeHear the best ways to give and take criticismUnderstand the necessity of writing effective email and formal architecture documentsGet tips for delivering confident career-building presentations to any audienceReview essential techniques for stakeholder management and relationship buildingExplore the critical needs for architecture reviews and an effective process for conducting themThrough lecture and small group exercises, Nathaniel will help you understand what it means to be a successful architect. Working through various problems, attendees will have opportunities to think through architectural decisions and patterns, discuss the importance of non functional requirements and why architects cannot afford to practice resume driven design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-youll-learn&#34;&gt;What you&amp;rsquo;ll learn&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discover the skill sets needed to juggle multiple priorities, meetings, and time demands&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn why your best team leadership tool is not a hammer but a shared cup of coffee&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hear the best ways to give and take criticism&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Understand the necessity of writing effective email and formal architecture documents&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get tips for delivering confident career-building presentations to any audience&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Review essential techniques for stakeholder management and relationship building&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explore the critical needs for architecture reviews and an effective process for conducting them&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;duration-1-3-days&#34;&gt;Duration: 1-3 Days&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
